David StancuSoftware Engineer

dstancu@nyu.edu
PGP 540FFD1702007D89
https://github.com/mach-kernel

78-42 147th St, #1A Kew Gardens Hills, NY 11367

about

My practice focuses on building fast, efficient, and maintainable software at scale to deliver impactful experiences. I have worked on a variety of systems varying from RTOS-enabled microcontrollers to large HA distributed systems. I firmly believe in a polyglot and interdisciplinary approach to problem solving: trying new things is crucial.

favorite buzzwords

ruby, javascript (es6+), python, elixir, erlang-otp, java, scala, kafka, rabbitmq, react, react-native, vue, elasticsearch, redis, mongodb, sql, heroku, kubernetes, AWS, git, gnu/linux, "map-reduce"

projects & oss

A HORE E HOE

ruby-grape/grape-roar

Easily schematize API responses to be HAL hypermedia compliant

mach-kernel/Scorpion

WinAPI object injector leveraging LoadLibiraryA and all compatible WH_* entry hooks

work experience

Catalyst

Senior Software Engineer 07/2017 - present

Leading software architecture for a CRM product in the customer success space. Designed real-time integrations stream with Salesforce.

Vericred

Senior Software Engineer 01/2016 - 09/2016

REST API architecture for real-time ingestion of health insurance data. Lead exploration with Hadoop streaming map-reduce jobs.

CMIT Solutions Manhattan
*nix/ESXi IT Engineer (06/2012 - 04/2014)

swagger-api/swagger-codegen

Complex shape serialization and OAuth support for Ruby, Python, PHP, and Java

karafka/karafka

Kafka framework for Ruby exposing powerful actor abstractions inspired by Akka, with "Rails-style" simplicity.

MyBankTracker

Senior Software Engineer 10/2016 - 06/2017

API architecture and ETL job design for maintenance of compliance data from clients. Heavy SEO optimizations, caching.

Dwolla

Developer Relations Engineer 04/2014 - 12/2015

Helped grow Dwolla API adoption as pivot between product and engineering teams. Wrote SDKs in C#, PHP, and Python.

MechoShade Systems

Web & IT Intern (10/2011 - 05/2012)

education

NYU Polytechnic School of Engineering BS Computer Science, 3.30 GPA

i18n

english (native), romanian (native), spanish (passable)